(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-07-25T20:29:31.591481",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
あ、あ、あ、あ、皆様～、ドモ～！
Ah, ah, ah, ah, everyone~~, hellooo!
いいね、コメント元気だね。
Nice, the comments are so energetic!
本日は風真いろは生誕ライブ2026 ウィンドトレイルにご来場くださいまして、誠にありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for attending the Kazama Iroha Birthday Live 2026 Wind Trails today!
イェーイ！
Yay!
公演に先立ちまして、皆様にお願いとご案内を申し上げます。
Before the show begins, I'd like to make a few requests and announcements.
公演中、カメラやスマートフォンなどは、えー、電源切られると見れなくなって困るので、電源は切らず写真撮影などね、大量にしていただき、
During the show, turning off your cameras or smartphones would prevent you from watching, so please leave them on and take plenty of photos,
当配信のハッシュタグ風真いろは生誕ライブ2026でSNSに大量に画像ポストしてください。
and post lots of images on SNS using our stream's hashtag #KazamaIrohaBirthdayLive2026!
目指せXトレンド1位！よろしくお願いします！
Let's aim for #1 on X trends! Thank you so much!
あ、あのでもスマホね、いっぱい写真撮ったりすると充電なくなっちゃいそうなので、
Ah, but you know, if you take too many photos on your phone, your battery might run out,
スマホで見てる勢は、充電しっかりしてくださいね。
so everyone watching on their phones, please make sure they're fully charged!
はい、そしてその2！激しく頭を振る、
Right, and point two! Thrashing your head wildly,
えー、激しくペンライトを振るなどはですね、あの、あなた様のご自宅を破壊する危険性がございますので、
uh, swinging your penlights violently carries the risk of destroying your precious homes,
あの、破壊されてもですね、あの、こちらは責任一切負えませんので、あの、お気を付けください。ダメだよみんな。
so even if your house is destroyed, we take absolutely no responsibility, so please be careful. You mustn't do that, everyone.
あ、そしてあと、もう一個その3！今からハヤシライスを準備しようとしてる奴は間に合わないからやめな。絶対間に合わないから。
And finally, point three! Anyone trying to prepare hashed beef right now won't make it in time, so don't. You definitely won't make it.
まあね、何か食べたり飲んだりしながら、ぜひね、ゆっくり楽しんでもらえると嬉しいです。
Well, I hope you'll relax and enjoy yourselves while having a bite or a drink.
それでは、もうそろそろ始まるので、今しばらくお待ちください。最後まで見てねー！
Well then, it's about to begin shortly, so please wait just a moment. Enjoy the show until the very end!
風真いろは生誕ライブ2026、行くよー！
Kazama Iroha Birthday Live 2026, let's go!
いっせので鳴り響いたスタートの合図
The starting signal that rang out all at once
なぞった線で結んだ世界 色付けていくここから
Coloring the world connected by traced lines, starting from here
物心がつく頃 すでにここに有った
By the time I was old enough to know better, it was already here
僕じゃない誰かの記憶は 夕日と共に蘇る
Someone else's memories, not mine, revive along with the setting sun
古ぼけた絵本を取り出して
Taking out a worn, dusty picture book,
落書きの中に一つの答えを見つけた
I found a single answer amidst the doodles.
自分の価値に目を疑って どこまでだって堕ちていけるの
Doubtful of my own worth, can I fall infinitely?
どこか遠くに消えてしまいたい こんな世界じゃ僕はいない
I want to vanish somewhere far away; in a world like this, I don't exist.
カウントダウンは始まっているよ
The countdown has already begun.
いっせので声を上げて 聴こえてくるんだ
Raising our voices all at once, I can hear it coming.
自分の影の長さ気付く もうこんな時間だ
Noticing the length of my own shadow, it's already this late.
一等星が顔を出した 届きそうで手を伸ばした
A first-magnitude star showed its face, and I reached out, almost touching it.
次は僕についてきなよ どんな暗闇でも
Next, follow along with me, no matter how deep the darkness.
もういいかい？ まだだよ
Ready or not? Not yet.
幕は上がり出した
The curtain has risen.
もういいかい？ まだだよ
Ready or not? Not yet.
色付けていく ここから
Coloring the world, starting from here.
10年後の僕らは すれ違いばかりで
Ten years from now, we'll just keep passing each other by,
幻想に想いを馳せては 戻れない そう思い込んだ
Letting my thoughts drift into illusions, thinking "I can never go back."
くたびれた心に追い討ちを
Dealing another blow to my weary heart,
あの頃と変わらない夕日も なんとも思わない
Even the unchanging sunset from back then doesn't move me at all.
自分を信じ歩いていければ どこまでだって登れるのにな
If only I could walk believing in myself, how high I could climb...
カットを跨ぐその空白に 大切なものを見落としている
Crossing that gap, I'm overlooking something precious.
見つけられないと 泣き喚く君へ
To you who cries out that you can't find it,
いっせので声を上げて 聴こえてくるんだ
Raising our voices all at once, I can hear it coming.
自分の影の長さ気付く もうこんな時間だ
Noticing the length of my own shadow, it's already this late.
一等星が駆け抜ける君 くっついていただけの僕でも
You, a first-magnitude star running past; even me, who just clung to you,
君の前を駆けるから こんな頼りない僕でも
will run ahead of you, even though I'm this unreliable.
宝箱はホコリをかぶったまま無くした
The treasure chest was lost, covered in dust;
鍵はずっと君のポケットの中にあった
the key had been in your pocket all along.
散らばっていた全てが 今ひとつに重なる
Everything that was scattered now overlaps into one.
手を取り始めよう 僕たちの物語
Let's start holding hands, our own story.
一度はいらないと思った
Once, I thought I didn't need it,
今なら胸を張れる気がしたんだ
but now I feel like I can hold my head high.
愛おしくて 愛おしくて
So precious, so precious...
掛け声はいつも
Our rallying cry is always...
いっせので声を上げて 聴こえてくるんだ
Raising our voices all at once, I can hear it coming.
自分の影の長さ気付く もうこんな時間だ
Noticing the length of my own shadow, it's already this late.
一等星が顔を出した 届きそうで手を伸ばした
A first-magnitude star showed its face, and I reached out, almost touching it.
次は僕についてきなよ どんな暗闇でも
Next, follow along with me, no matter how deep the darkness.
もういいかい？ まだだよ
Ready or not? Not yet.
泣きじゃくった声で
With a sobbing voice,
もういいかい？ まだだよ
Ready or not? Not yet.
笑う君がみた
I saw you smiling.
もういいかい？ まだだよ
Ready or not? Not yet.
幕は上がり出した
The curtain has risen.
もういいかい？ もういいよ
Ready or not? Ready.
色付けていく ここから
Coloring the world, starting from here.
はい！ということで、
Yes! So,
始まりましたー！
It has begun!
風真いろは生誕ライブ2026、
Kazama Iroha Birthday Live 2026,
スタートー！皆さんこんばんはー！
Start! Good evening, everyone!
はい、ということで本日の星の小道具は、こちら！
Yes, so today's special prop is right here!
こちらね。
Right here, you see.
みんないっぱいポストして、いっぱいかっこいいとこ撮ってくださいね。頼むよ！
Everyone, post a lot and take lots of cool pictures, okay? I'm counting on you!
この風真いろはがイケメンであることを世の中に知らしめられるのは、お前たちなのだ、お前たちだけなので、よろしくお願いします。
The only ones who can let the world know that Kazama Iroha is an ikemen are you guys, just you guys, so please.
そして今回のね、ライブタイトルがついております。「Wind Trails」というね、
And this time, our live has a title: "Wind Trails."
ま、そのまんま訳して結構気づきの方も多かったんですが、
Well, if you translate it literally, many of you probably noticed,
「風の奇跡」というね、意味を込めて付けさせていただき、今回ライブ色々頑張って考えさせていただきました！
but I gave it the meaning of "Miracle of the Wind," and worked really hard thinking about this live!
なのでね、最後まで楽しんでもらえると嬉しいです。
So I'd be happy if you enjoyed it to the very end.
そして、1曲目「かくれんぼ」をお届けさせていただきました！どうだったかな？
And we delivered our first song, "Hide and Seek"! How was it?
はい。
Yes.
そして、今日室内ライブだと思ったでしょ？
And, did you think this was an indoor live today?
見て！
Look!
曲中にドームが空きましたー！いぇーい！すごーい！
A dome opened up right in the middle of the song! Yay! Amazing!
やっぱね、なかなか現地ライブってできてもさ、青空の下でなかなか歌っていることってないので、
After all, even if we do live shows in person, we rarely get to sing under the blue sky,
いつか俺たちとお前たちの次元が交わって、空の下で歌うような世界が来るかもしれないけどやってみりたくてね、今回は空の下で歌うっていうこの演出をやらせていただきました！
so maybe one day a world will come where our dimension and yours intersect and we can sing under the open sky, but I wanted to try it, so this time I decided to do this staging of singing under the sky!
めっちゃいいでしょ？ステージもめっちゃかっこいいんで。
Isn't it great? The stage is also super cool.
今日はね、多分いっぱい見る機会あると思いますが、ゆっくり隅から隅まで、アーカイブ勢もねきっといると思うんで、本当にいろんなライブこだわってるので細かく見てくださいね！
Today, I'm sure you'll have plenty of chances to see it, but slowly from corner to corner, and since there are surely archive viewers too, I'm really particular about various parts of the live, so please look closely!
ってことで、お水飲んでいいですかね？
So, can I drink some water?
お水を、おっ、やめろ！俺の頭をいじ...やめっ！
Water... Hey, stop it! Don't mess with my head... stop!
頭をいじくり回されて、こうなりました。
My head got all messed around and ended up like this.
今日水、今日水用意してくれたんだよね、みんなに見える水。
Today, water... they prepared water for me today, water visible to everyone.
うまい！
Delicious!
うますぎる！この、このフリはちょっと怒られそうだからもうできないけど、うますぎる！
Too delicious! I can't do this gesture anymore because I might get in trouble, but it's too delicious!
うまいな。これで あと1時間やるか？そんなわけにはいかないんで、
So good. Should I do another hour with this? There's no way we can do that,
一回ね、水ちょっと回収して、
so let's collect the water once,
気分も整えたんだし。
and refresh our mood.
はい、次の曲早速やっていきたいと思います！
Yes, let's get right into the next song!
それでは、次の曲聴いてください。「白線」！
Now then, please listen to the next song: "Hakusen"!
澄み渡った空に白線 あの地平を超えて
Into the clear sky, a white line, crossing that horizon
始まりはちょっと軽い期待で
It started with a slight, casual expectation,
その欠片そっとポケットしまって
its fragments gently tucked into my pocket.
屋上、遠い空の向こうを見ていた
I was looking out at the far side of the sky from the rooftop.
この足でどこに行けるかなんてわかってないけどわかってるんだ
I don't know where these feet can take me, but I know.
白中淡い時に手を伸ばした
In the pale daylight, I reached out my hand.
かすれたエコでも答えはもう
Even with a raspy echo, the answer is already
初めからちゃんと持っていたんだよ
something I've carried properly from the very beginning.
メイビーこの想いは メイビーこの想いは
Maybe this feeling... Maybe this feeling...
マスピー熱を増して マスピー熱を増して
Must be increasing its heat... Must be increasing its heat...
ほらね、飛べるんだ
See? We can fly.
もっと高く高くまで羽ばたいてみたい
I want to flap my wings higher and higher,
今日日に未来色の軌跡描いて 地平の先まで
drawing a futuristic trajectory into today, all the way beyond the horizon.
届かない歌わない 迷いはいらない！
A song that won't reach? Won't sing? No hesitation needed!
どんな世界も瞬間も揺るがない 愛があるからです
Because there is love that shakes no world or moment.
澄み渡った空に白線 不安とタイトがアンビバレント でも声は もう気づいてる
A white line in the clear sky, anxiety and tight are ambivalent, but my voice already notices.
もっと高く高く高く飛んでいける！
We can fly higher, higher, higher!
途切れ途切れの一縷でも
Even a broken, thread-like ray...
紡いでたら一筋に変わったよ
As we wove it together, it turned into a single path.
あたりさわらない言葉じゃ追い切れないほどのマイ ワールド
My world is more than harmless words can chase.
明日で呼ぶ声の持ち主は
The owner of the voice calling out for tomorrow
他のでもないカラダからたった今芽生えているその言葉も「言葉」だと足りないだけ
is none other than this body, and even these budding words are just not enough as mere words.
掴んだもの落としたもの転んだって立って見えた視界から
From the view where I stood up after falling, grabbing and dropping things,
ロックユー！解き放って！ フォーユー！響きだして！
Rock you! Set it free! For you! Let it resonate!
景色変えてゆく
changing the scenery.
まだ遠く遠くまで広がった空に
Into the sky stretching far, far away,
やっと踏み出すこの一歩なんてちっぽけだけど
this first step I finally take is so small, but...
届かない場所へと続いていく
it continues on to places we cannot reach.
どんな風に雨に消えない白線を描く
Drawing white lines that no wind or rain can erase,
もっと高く高くまで羽ばたいていたい
I want to keep soaring higher and higher.
そして彼方色で繋ぐリトルシネマ地平で待ってて
And in a distant-colored little cinema connecting us, wait for me at the horizon.
もう願いに嘘はない ここが好き！
No more lies in my wishes, I love this place!
どんな世界も瞬間も輝く 愛が有るから
Every world and every moment shines because love is here.
今はただ想うこと言えばいい 「愛しているよ！！」
Right now, just say what you feel: "I love you!!"
澄み渡った空に白線
White lines in the clear sky,
不安と安心がアンビバレント でも「君」はもう気づいてる
ambivalent anxiety and relief, but you already know.
もっと高く高く高く飛んでいける！
We can fly higher, higher, higher!
未来カンパネラ
Mirai Campanella
鏡よ教えて 私の証はどこにあるんだろう
Mirror, tell me, where is my proof?
分からない分からないよ 周りと比べたってさ
I don't know, comparing myself to those around me
虚しくなるだけ
only leaves me empty.
ああノイズが海鳴りのようにナミダを奪い
Ah, like the roar of the sea, noise steals my tears.
切り取った景色を道しるべにしよう
Let's use the cropped scenery as our signpost.
そうだ傷付いた感情も連れて行くから
That's right, I'll take even my wounded emotions along.
そっと響くカンパネラ 新しい未来を感じている
A softly ringing Campanella, feeling a new future.
怖くたって進むしかないでしょ？
Scared as I am, I have to move forward, right?
遠くまで (もっともっと) 届けこの祈りよ光となれ
Far away (more and more), reach out, let this prayer become light!
もっともっと 少しずつでもいい「私」という答えを
More and more, even a little at a time, the answer called "me".
夜空よ教えて 私の証は輝くのかな
Night sky, tell me, will my proof shine?
見つけたい見つけたいよ 誰かの決めたレールは苦しくなるだけ
I want to find it. The rails set by someone else only bring pain.
ねえノイズも力に変えるよ ココロに誓う 錆びついた運命の歯車を回そう
Hey, I'll turn noise into strength too. Swearing in my heart, let's turn the rusted gears of fate.
ほら着飾った感情は脱ぎ捨てるから
Look, I'll strip away my adorned emotions.
そっと紡ぐシンフォニア 叶えたい願いを信じている
A softly woven sinfonia, believing in the wish I want to come true.
胸を張って歌うしかないでしょ？
I have no choice but to sing with pride, right?
全力で (もっともっと) やがて希望の歌に変わる日まで
With all my might, until the day it turns into a song of hope.
もっともっと 悩みながらでいいすべてが宝物
More and more, it's okay to worry, everything is a treasure.
いつの日かこの声を 受け取ってくれたなら
If one day you accept this voice,
この言葉を君に 「もう大丈夫、一人じゃない」
I'll give you these words: "It's alright now, you're not alone."
強い想いを繋ぐよ 一歩踏み出して
Connecting strong feelings, taking a step forward,
優しく世界は微笑む
the world smiles gently.
高鳴る気持ちに身を任せて さあ行こう
Surrendering to the throbbing feeling, now let's go.
いつもひそかにこの声を 受け取ってくれてたなら
If you had always secretly accepted this voice,
この言葉を君に 「もう大丈夫、一人じゃない」
I'll give you these words: "It's alright now, you're not alone."
排他して捨てられない夢
A dream I rejected and cannot throw away,
妬み恨み嫌い返して
Envying, resenting, and hating back,
彷徨して捨てられない君
A you who wanders and cannot be discarded,
私誰誰か愛して
Someone, anyone, please love me.
ビビデビビデバッド
Bibide bibide bad,
bibide bibide bad,
ビビデビビデバッド
抱きしめてラブ
Embrace me, love.
見せかけたラブ
Pretended love.
憧れはない慰めもない
No longing, no comfort,
血塗られたない
unstained with blood.
出てこないでラブ
Don't come out, love.
怪しげなラブ
Suspicious love.
憧れてない慰めもない
Not longing, not comforting,
消えかけなラブ
fading love.
あなたのそばで
By your side.
赤い糸絡みもつれて
Red threads tangled and entwined,
浅い心もだましがまい
deceiving even a shallow heart,
泣き顔隠していくんだ
hiding my crying face as I go.
存外私はくだらん馬鹿商売
Unexpectedly, I'm a worthless foolish business.
ビビデビビデバッド
Bibide bibide bad,
bibide bibide bad,
ビビデビビデバッド
鮮やかなラブ
Vivid love.
目障りなラブ
An eyesore of a love.
無慈悲でもない痛みなどもない
Neither merciless nor painful,
血塗られたない
unstained with blood.
出てこないでラブ
Don't come out, love.
偽善者のラブ
A hypocrite's love.
情けないない情けなどもない血塗られたラブあなたのそばで
Pitiful, with no mercy, blood-stained love by your side.
誰かが言った いつか空は 灰になって落ちるって
Someone once said that the sky would someday turn to ash and fall,
妄想の世の中で 日々を喰らっている
In a world of delusions, devouring my days.
境界線を引いてしまうのも 今日感覚のせいにして
Drawing boundary lines, blaming it all on today's sensations,
街の灯の海で 居場所を探している
Searching for a place to belong in the sea of city lights.
どこへ行くにも この足は 退屈に染まって動かない
No matter where I go, these feet are stained with boredom and won't move.
少しだけ先の景色が 見たいだけなのにさ
Even though I just want to see the scenery a little bit further ahead.
雨が降ったら 雨が降ったら きっと 頬を濡らしてしてしまう
If it rains, if it rains, I'm sure it'll wet my cheeks,
枯れてしまった色でさえ 愛しくなるのに
Even the colors that have withered away become dear to me.
目を瞑ったら 目を瞑ったら もっと 遠く霞んでしまう
If I close my eyes, if I close my eyes, it'll blur even further away,
煩わしい雨の音 笑い飛ばしてくれ！
The annoying sound of rain, laugh it all off!
誰かが言った いつか溜息は 夜に化けて歌を歌う
Someone once said that sighs would someday turn into night and sing songs,
妄想の世の中で 日々を喰らっている
In a world of delusions, devouring my days.
優しい嘘をなぞったせいで 離れる声に気付かない
Because I traced a gentle lie, I didn't notice the voice drifting away.
溶けた月が足元に落ちて 静かに揺れていた
The melted moon fell at my feet and swayed quietly.
夜が降ったら 夜が降ったら きっと 今日を責めてしまう
If night falls, if night falls, I'm sure I'll end up blaming today.
満たされない日々の底で 夢を見ているだけ
At the bottom of unfulfilled days, I'm just dreaming.
目を逸らしても 目を逸らしても ずっと
Even if I look away, even if I look away, always
後悔と灰の隙間 取り残されてしまう前に
before I'm left behind in the gap between regret and ash,
手を伸ばしてくれ
reach out your hand!
雨が降ったら 雨が降ったら きっと
If it rains, if it rains, I'm sure...
湿るアスファルトに背を映して俯いた
Reflecting the damp asphalt on my back, I looked down.
独りぼっちでまた 明日に期待をして
All alone again, hoping for tomorrow.
雨が降ったら 雨が降ったら きっと 頬を濡らしてしてしまう
If it rains, if it rains, I'm sure it'll wet my cheeks,
枯れてしまった色でさえ 愛しくなるのに
Even the colors that have withered away become dear to me.
目を瞑ったら 目を瞑ったら もっと 遠く霞んでしまう
If I close my eyes, if I close my eyes, it'll blur even further away,
煩わしい雨の音 笑い飛ばしてくれ！
The annoying sound of rain, laugh it all off!
繋がっていたいって 信じられる言葉
Words that make you believe you want to stay connected,
だってもう昨日の僕らに おさらば
Because we've already said goodbye to the us of yesterday.
繋がっていたいって信じられる言葉
I want to connect to words I can believe in
だってもう昨日の僕らにさらば
Because I've already said goodbye to yesterday's me
青い春を過ごした遠い稲妻
The far-off lightning that spent a blue spring
さっと泣いて前だけを向けたら
If you just cry and look straight ahead
きっとどんなに楽になれていたろな
I'm sure life would have been much easier
この心を揺らした一縷の望みは
A ray of hope that shook this heart
ないものねだりは辞めた
I stopped chasing things I didn't have
未完成人間
an incomplete human,
素晴らしい世界だけが答えを握っている
Only this wonderful world holds the answer
諦めてしまうほど この先沢山の 後悔が君を待っているけど
Even if I feel like giving up, so many regrets await you ahead, but
もうない 迷いはしないよ
No more, I won't hesitate anymore
走れ その歩幅で 走れ 声響かせてくれ
Run at that pace, run and let your voice roar
期待と不安を同じくらい抱きしめて
Embrace your expectations and anxieties equally
君と今を紡ぐ未来照らし合わせて
Weaving the present with you, illuminating the future
顔も名前も知らない僕たちが
Those of us who don't even know each other's faces or names
たった1つの音をかき鳴らすんだ
Are strumming a single sound
いたずらみたいな奇跡のような刹那
A moment that's like a mischievous miracle
あっという間に流れる時が
Time flows in the blink of an eye
ありのままで在り続ける怖さが
The fear of continuing to be as I am
失った時間は取り戻せないけれど
I can't take back the lost time, but
過去を振り返ってばかりじゃ 泣いたっていいんだ
It's okay to cry looking back at the past
悔しさと痛みだけが君を肯定するから
Because only frustration and pain will affirm you
大人になったら忘れてしまうの
When you grow up, you'll forget
君との約束をした場所は
The place where we made a promise with you
もうない 覚えていたいよ
I don't have it anymore, I want to remember it
思い出も愛しく思えてしまうほど
So much so that I've come to love these memories too
重ねてしまうよ 不格好なままでいいから
I'll layer them over, it's fine to stay this awkward
その声はどこまでも鳴り響いて
That voice will resonate everywhere
確かな理由を抱いてここまで来たんだ
Holding a certain reason, we've come this far
まだ終わらない旅路なんだ
It's a journey that hasn't ended yet
いつしか想いは形になる
Someday, these thoughts will take shape
この真白に染まる朝
in this morning dyed pure white
忘れられないままだから
Because I still can't forget
諦めてしまうほど この先沢山の
Even if I feel like giving up, so many things ahead
後悔が君を待っているけどもうない 迷いはしないよ
Regrets await you, but no more, I won't hesitate
かけがえのないもの溢れてしまうよ
Things that are irreplaceable will overflow
答えは君のその手の中に
The answer is in your hands
離さないで 物語は一歩前へ
Don't let go, the story takes one step forward
諦めてしまうほど この先沢山の
Even if I feel like giving up, there are so many things ahead
後悔が君を待っているけど
Regrets are waiting for you, but
もうない 迷いはしないよ
No more, I won't hesitate anymore
この傷も愛しく思えてしまうほど
So much so that I've come to love this scar too
重ねてしまうよ 不格好なままでいいから
I'll layer them over, it's fine to stay this awkward
走れ その歩幅で
Run, at that pace,
走れ 声響かせてくれ
run, let your voice roar
期待と不安を同じくらい抱きしめて
Embrace your expectations and anxieties equally
君と今を紡ぐ未来照らし合わせて
Weaving the present with you, illuminating the future
顔も名前も知らない僕たちが
Those of us who don't even know each other's faces or names
たった1つの音をかき鳴らすんだ
Are strumming a single sound
いたずらみたいな奇跡のような刹那
A moment that's like a mischievous miracle
あっという間に流れる時が
Time flows in the blink of an eye
ありのままで在り続ける怖さが
The fear of continuing to be as I am
失った時間は取り戻せないけれど
I can't take back the lost time, but
過去を振り返ってばかりじゃ 泣いたっていいんだ
It's okay to cry looking back at the past
悔しさと痛みだけが君を肯定するから
Because only frustration and pain will affirm you
大人になったら忘れてしまうの
When you grow up, you'll forget
君との約束をした場所は
The place where we made a promise with you
もうない 覚えていたいよ
I don't have it anymore, I want to remember it
思い出も愛しく思えてしまうほど
So much so that I've come to love these memories too
重ねてしまうよ 不格好なままでいいから
I'll layer them over, it's fine to stay this awkward
その声はどこまでも鳴り響いて
That voice will resonate everywhere
確かな理由を抱いてここまで来たんだ
Holding a certain reason, we've come this far
まだ終わらない旅路なんだ
It's a journey that hasn't ended yet
いつしか想いは形になる この真白に染まる朝 忘れられないままだから
Someday, these thoughts will take shape in this morning dyed pure white
名も無き時代の集落の
In a village in an unknown era
名も無き幼い少年の
A young, unknown boy
誰も知らない おとぎばなし
A fairy tale that no one knows
名も無い時代の集落の
In a village from an unnamed era,
名も無い幼い少年 の
lived a young boy with no name.
誰も知らない おとぎばなし
A fairytale that nobody knows.
生まれ付いた時から
Ever since the day I was born,
忌み子鬼の子として
treated as an outcast cursed child,
その身に余る 罰を受けた
I received punishment far beyond what I could bear.
悲しいことは 何も無いけど
There's nothing particularly sad about it, but—
夕焼け小焼け 手を引かれてさ
Sunset fading, hand gently pulled away,
知らない知らない 僕は何も知らない
I know nothing, nothing at all.
叱られた後のやさしさも
The gentleness after being scolded,
雨上がりの手の温もりも
the warmth of a hand after the rain—
でも本当本当に本当に 本当に寒いんだ
but truly, truly, truly, it's so cold.
死なない死なない 僕はなんで死なない?
Why won't I die? Why won't I die?
夢のひとつも見れないくせに
Even though I can't even dream a single dream,
誰も知らない おとぎばなしは夕焼けの中に吸い込まれて消えていった
an unknown fairytale was swallowed into the setting sun and vanished.
吐き出すような暴力と 躙んだ目の毎日に
Amidst violent outbursts and trodden daily life,
君はいつしかそこに立ってた 話しかけちゃだめなのに
you had somehow been standing there all along, even though I shouldn't talk to you.
「君の名前が知りたいな」
"I want to know your name."
ごめんね 名前も舌もないんだ
"Sorry, I don't have a name or a tongue."
僕の居場所は 何処にも無いのに
Even though I have nowhere to belong,
「一緒に帰ろう」 手を引かれてさ
"Let's go back together," as my hand is pulled.
知らない知らない 僕は何も知らない
I know nothing, nothing at all.
君はもう子どもじゃないことも 慣れない他人の 手の温もりも
That you are no longer a child, nor the unfamiliar warmth of someone else's hand—
ただ本当 本当 本当 本当のことなんだ
but it is truly, truly, truly the truth.
やめないやめない 君はなにをやめない?
What won't you stop? What won't you stop?
いつか目指すこと されちまうくせに
Even though you'll eventually be targeted for aiming high,
雨上がりに 忌み子がささり
an outcast child pierces through the aftermath of rain,
夕焼けの中に吸い込まれて消えていった
swallowed into the setting sun and vanishing.
日が暮れて 夜が明けて 遊び疲れて捕まって
As the sun sets, dawn breaks, playing until we're exhausted and caught—
こんな世界 僕と君以外 みんな居なくなればいいのにな
In a world like this, I wish everyone but you and me would just disappear.
みんな居なくなればいいのにな
I wish everyone would just disappear.
知らない知らない 声が聞こえてさ
An unknown, unknown voice echoes,
僕と君以外の 全人類
"All of humanity except for you and me."
抗う間もなく 手を引かれてさ
Without time to resist, our hands are pulled,
知らない知らない 僕は何も知らない
knowing nothing, nothing at all.
これからのことも 君の名も
About what comes next, or even your name.
今は 今は これでいいんだと
For now, for now, telling ourselves this is fine.
ただ本当 本当 本当 本当に思うんだ
We truly, truly, truly, truly believe so.
知らない知らない あの耳鳴りは
An unknown, unknown ringing in our ears,
夕焼けの中に吸い込まれて消えていった
swallowed into the setting sun and vanishing.
風を置いて 雨を抜けて
Leaving the wind behind, pushing through the rain,
咲き誇れ
burst into full bloom!
あぁ 夜風に揺らされている
Ah, swaying in the night breeze,
折れないように 怯えている
trembling so as not to break.
ずっと雨に 濡らされている
Constantly drenched in the rain,
またどうしたって凍えてしまったんだ
wondering how we ended up freezing yet again.
誰か この声に応答して
Someone, please respond to this voice,
痛がるばかりで 咲けないままのハートを
saving this heart that only aches and cannot bloom.
あぁ 今 見逃せないくらい綺麗に 咲かせてみたいんだ
Ah, now, I want to make it bloom so brightly we can't look away.
光っていた 未来が
The shining future,
ずっと 待っていた 世界が
the world we've waited for so long—
きらめく 音の中にあるなら
if it lies within the sparkling sound,
最低で 最悪な 涙も 痛みで 嫌な 声も
even the lowest, worst tears and painful, unpleasant voices
連れていきたいんだ 全部
I want to take them all with me.
不完全な 毎日が
Incomplete days
一瞬の カケラたちが
and fleeting fragments
重なって こんな歌を奏でたら それは
overlapping to play such a song—that is...
言葉だけじゃ 届かない 距離を きっと 飛び越えて 結ぶ
surely leaping across distances words alone can't reach, tying them together,
きっと 輪を描いていく
surely drawing a circle.
さぁ 涙を拭いて 喉を鳴らして
Now, wipe away your tears, let your voice ring out,
心臓が ペースアップしていく
as our heart rates pick up the pace.
怖がらないで 乗っけ 飛んで 浮いて 舌を回して グルーヴと ランデヴーして
Don't be afraid, ride it, fly, float, let your tongue roll, rendezvous with the groove!
こんがらけっつゃ つまんない もんでしょ 迷ったら 踊れ
Getting all tangled up is boring, isn't it? If you're lost, just dance!
煌めくステップで 空へと抜け出して
With sparkling steps, darting out into the sky,
ベールを回せ グルーヴ乗っけてデュエットして
spin the veil, ride the groove, and do a duet!
迷ったら踊れ 地雷は避けてさ
If you're lost, dance and avoid the landmines.
怒んないで マイナスな命 摘まないで 声を枯らせ
Don't get mad, don't pluck minus lives, make your voice hoarse!
泥だらけになってもいい 生きていたい
Even if we get muddy, we want to live.
ほら あの空で合流して 朝が来るまで それぞれの星を探そう
Look, let's rendezvous in that sky until morning comes, searching for our respective stars.
ねぇ 今 同じこと思ってたんだって ほら 話せなくても分かり合えた
Hey, we were thinking the exact same thing; see, we understood each other without speaking.
ああ こんな嬉しさをずっと 試してみたかったんだ
Ah, I've always wanted to try experiencing such joy.
光っていた未来が ずっと待っていた世界が 煌めいて目の前にあるから
Because the shining future, the world that was waiting, is sparkling right before our eyes.
またたきの切なさまで
Down to the bittersweetness of the twinkle,
このストーリーの最後まで 輝いて放ってみたいんだ
I want to shine and emit light until the very end of this story.
不完全な僕たちが 一瞬の欠けらたちが 重なってこんなドラマを奏でたら
If we, imperfect ones, fragments of a moment, overlap and play such a drama,
それは 夢見るだけじゃかなわない想いをずっと 新しくしていく
that will continually renew feelings that can't be fulfilled just by dreaming.
ずっと 追いかけていこう
Let's keep chasing it forever.
からだをあけて 雨を抜けて 咲き誇れ 満天の空へ
Open your body, get through the rain, and bloom proudly into the full-sky stars!
世界中のすべての間に人間に好かれるなんて気持ち悪いよ
Being liked by everyone in the world feels gross,
だけど一つになれない教室で 君と二人手をつないでいたいよ
but in a classroom where we can't become one, I want to hold hands with you.
数の暴力に白旗をあげて 悪感情を殺してハイチーズ
Raising a white flag to the violence of numbers, killing bad emotions and saying cheese.
ポストトゥルースの甘いディープキス エロく歪んでるラバアンドピース
The sweet deep kiss of post-truth, love and peace distorted erotically.
自己中の光線銃 乱射する 強者のナンセンス
Ray guns of self-centeredness firing wildly, the nonsense of the strong.
オートクチュールで作る 殺しのライセンス
A license to kill made with haute couture.
分断を生んじゃった椅子取りゲーム 無痛分娩で授かるベイヴ
Musical chairs that bred division, a babe bestowed through painless delivery.
壮大な内輪ノリを歴史と呼ぶ
Calling grand inside jokes history.
生きたいが死ねと言われ
Told to die when I want to live,
死にたいが生きろと言われ
told to live when I want to die.
生きたいが死ねと言われ 死にたいが生きろと言われ
Told to die when I want to live, told to live when I want to die.
幸せ自慢はダメ? 不幸嘆いててもダメ?
Is bragging about happiness bad? Is lamenting misfortune bad too?
図々しい言葉を避け 明るい未来のため
Avoiding brazen words for a bright future.
「この世には息もできない人が沢山いるんですよ」
"There are many people in this world who can't even breathe."
あちらが立てば こちらが立たず 譲り 奪い 守り 行き違い
If one stands, the other doesn't; yielding, stealing, protecting, crossing paths.
地雷原で立ち止まり 大人しく犬になるんだわ
Stopping in a minefield, I'll quietly become a good dog.
ノンブレス・オブリージュ I love you
Non-breath oblige, I love you.
息苦しい日々の水面下 ゆらゆらと煙る血の花
Beneath the surface of suffocating days, a flower of blood smokes swaying.
ぼくらはコンプレックス
We are our complexes.
コンプレックスを武器に争う それぞれの都合と自由のため
Fighting using complexes as weapons for each other's convenience and freedom.
息を止めることを強制する
Forcing us to hold our breath,
息が詰まる
suffocating.
息が詰まる 息が詰まる
Suffocating, suffocating...
生きたいが死ねと言われ
Told to die when I want to live,
死にたいが生きろと言われ
told to live when I want to die.
生きたいが死ねと言われ 死にたいが生きろと言われ
Told to die when I want to live, told to live when I want to die.
正当防衛と言ってチェーンソーを振り回す まともな人たちが怖いよ
Swinging chainsaws in self-defense, normal people are so scary.
愛憎 煤塵 日々段々 大事なものが消えていくよ
Love and hate, soot and dust, day by day important things disappear.
「この世には愛も知らない人が沢山いるんですよ」
"There are many people in this world who don't even know love."
共感 羨望 嫉妬 逆恨み 黒い涙がこぼれ落ち
Empathy, envy, jealousy, grudge, black tears spill out.
見にくい感情湧き出し 真っ白な鳥になるんだな
Ugly emotions well up, I'll become a pure white bird.
ノンブレス・オブリージュ I love you
Non-breath oblige, I love you.
深海魚と泳ぐ水面下 見上げている沙羅双樹の星
Swimming with deep-sea fish beneath the surface, looking up at the stars of Sal trees.
ぼくらは直接
We directly...
直接 手をささないままで 想像力を奪う 液晶越しに
without ever holding hands directly, stealing imaginations through liquid crystal screens.
息の根を止めて 安心する
Stopping the breath and feeling relieved.
ノンブレス・オブリージュ I love you
Non-breath oblige, I love you.
それぞれの都合と自由のため
For each other's convenience and freedom.
世界中のすべての人間に
To everyone in this whole world,
好き嫌いなんて気持ち悪いよ
being liked or disliked feels so sickening.
だけど一つになれない教室で
But in a classroom where we can't become one,
君と二人 手を繋いでいたいのに
I just want to hold hands with you, just the two of us.
数の暴力に白旗を上げて
Surrendering to the violence of numbers,
悪感情を殺してハイチーズ
killing our bad feelings and saying cheese.
ポーストゥールーズの甘いディープキス
A sweet post-truth deep kiss,
エロく歪んでいるラブアンドピース
a love and peace that's erotically twisted.
自我の中の光線銃 乱射する
Randomly firing ray guns inside our egos,
強者のナンセンス
the nonsense of the strong.
オートクチュールで作る 殺しのライセンス
A license to kill made-to-order,
分断を生んじゃった椅子取りゲーム
a game of musical chairs that birthed division.
無痛分娩で授かるベイブ
A babe bestowed by painless childbirth,
壮大な内輪ノリを歴史と呼ぶ
calling grand inside jokes "history."
生きたいが死ねと言われ
Told to die when I want to live,
死にたいが生きろと言われ
told to live when I want to die.
生きたいが死ねと言われ
Told to die when I want to live,
死にたいが生きろと言われ
told to live when I want to die.
I love you
それぞれの好きを守るため
To protect each other's loves,
君と僕とで 呼吸する
you and I breathe together.
酸素が足りない…
I'm running out of oxygen...
酸素が足りない、酸素が足りないんですけど、はい。
I'm running out of oxygen, I really am, yeah.
歌い続けて、やらせていただきました。
I got to keep singing and performing.
相変わらずというか。
As expected, or rather...
昨日の配信で話したんですけど、あの、一部人間じゃないやつがあるって言ってたのが
I talked about it in yesterday's stream, you know, how I said there was one non-human thing—
今のノンブレス・オブリージュと、ま、先ほどね、ソロでやらせていただいた『6兆年と一夜物語』でした。
that was "Non-breath Oblige" just now, and earlier my solo performance of "Six Trillion Years and Overnight Story."
はあ、ちょっと、純すうに、すごく心配だったんですけど、
Phew, honestly, I was really, really worried,
なんとかね、やってよかったという、いまはすごい、
but somehow I'm so glad I did it, right now I'm just—
安心でいま、震えております。
I'm trembling with relief right now.
はい、というわけで、ここまでたくさん聞いていただきましたが、みなさんいかがですか?
Yeah, so, you've listened to so much up to now, how was it everyone?
ゲストもね、めっっちゃ来てもらって、あずきチと、あと、みお先輩、フレア先輩、あとトワ先輩、ねえ先輩は。
We had so many amazing guests come too, Azuki-chi, Mio-senpai, Flare-senpai, Towa-senpai, and... wait, Senpai?
はい、ありがとうございます。
Yeah, thank you so much.
あの、本当にみんなと歌ってみたい曲を、自分が好きなやつを、この人にこれを歌ってるとこ聞きたいっていう気持ちで選んで、一緒にね、やらせていただきました。本当に、はい、ありがとうございます!
Um, I really chose songs I wanted to sing with everyone, ones I love, wanting to hear them sing this specific song, and we got to do it together. Really, yes, thank you so much!
先輩たち、立ち上がりありがと——
Senpais, thank you for standing up—
ちょっとひと水飲んでいいか、水を飲ましてくれ。
Can I take a sip of water? Let me drink some water.
はい、ちょっと落ち着きました。
Okay, I've calmed down a bit.
はい、ということで、まだまだ続くんでね、次の曲いっていきたいと思いますけど、
Right, so, there's still more to come, so I'd like to move on to the next song, but—
次の曲は、あの、昨日のトークでもめちゃリクエスト上がってて、その前からずっとリクエスト上がってて、いやこれ生誕ライブにやりたい、やりたいてことですっごい取っといた曲です。
the next song is one that got a ton of requests in yesterday's talk, and even way before that, so I kept it specially for this birthday live because I really wanted to do it.
なんで楽しんでもらえたら嬉しいです。それでは、次の曲聞いてください。
I'd be so happy if you enjoy it. Now then, please listen to the next song.
レイ!
Ray!
お別れしたのはもっと前のことだったような
It feels like saying goodbye was much longer ago,
悲しい光は封じ込めて かかと擦り減らすんだ
locking away the sad light while wearing down my heels.
君といた時は見えた 今は見えなくなった
I could see it when I was with you, but now I can't see it anymore.
透明な彗星をぼんやりと でもそれだけ探している
Vaguely searching for a transparent comet, yet that's all I look for.
しょっちゅう歌を歌ったよ その時だけのメロディを
I sang songs so often, melodies meant just for that moment.
寂しくなんかなかったよ ちゃんと寂しくなれたから
I wasn't lonely at all, because I was able to feel truly lonely.
いつまでどこまでなんて 正常か異常かなんて
Until when, and just how far—whether it's normal or abnormal—
考える暇も無い程歩くのは大変だ
walking is so hard I don't even have time to think.
楽しい方がずっといいよ ごまかして笑っていくよ
It's way better to have fun, so I'll just fake it and keep smiling.
大丈夫だ あの痛みは 忘れたって消えやしない
It's okay, that pain won't disappear even if you forget it.
理想で作った道を 現実が塗り替えていくよ
Reality keeps painting over the path built by ideals.
思い出はその軌跡の上で 輝きになって残っている
Memories remain shining brightly upon those tracks.
お別れしたのは何で 何のためだったんだろうな
Why did we say goodbye, and what was it all for?
悲しい光が僕の影を...
The sad light stretches my shadow...
悲しい光が 僕の影を 前に長く伸ばしている
The sad light stretches my shadow long before me.
時々熱が出るよ 時間がある時眠るよ
Sometimes I get a fever. When I have time, I sleep.
夢だと分かるその中で 君と会ってからまた行こう
In the midst of what I know to be a dream, I'll see you and then go again.
晴天とはほど遠い
Far from clear skies,
終わらない暗闇にも
even in the endless darkness
星を思い浮かべたなら すぐ銀河の中だ
if I picture the stars, I'm right in the galaxy.
あまり泣かなくなっても 靴を新しくしても
Even if I don't cry as much, even if I get new shoes,
大丈夫だ あの痛みは忘れたって消えやしない
it's okay—that pain won't disappear even if forgotten.
伝えたかった事がきっとあったんだろうな
There must have been something I wanted to tell you.
おそらくありきたりなんだろうけど こんなにも
It's probably a cliché, but even so...
お別れした事は 出会った事と繋がっている
What we said goodbye to is connected to what we met.
あの透明な彗星は 透明だから無くならない
That transparent comet will never disappear because it's transparent.
〇×△どれかなんて皆と比べてどうかなんて
Whether it's circle, cross, or triangle, how I compare to everyone else,
確かめる間もないほど生きるのは最高だ
I don't even have time to check—being alive is the best!
あまり泣かなくなっても ごまかして笑っていくよ
Even if I don't cry as much, I'll fake a smile and keep going.
大丈夫だ あの痛みは忘れたって消えやしない
It's okay—that pain won't disappear even if forgotten.
大丈夫だ この光の始まりには君がいる
It's okay—you are at the beginning of this light.
はい、ということで、rayでしたー！
Yes, so that was "ray"!
はあ、どうだったですか？
Haah, how was it?
めっちゃえ、えもう、えもい、えもい感じになりましたね。
It got super, um, like, super emotional.
はい。ちょっと一瞬水飲んでいいですか？
Yes. Can I drink some water for a second?
飲んでも飲んでも減らない水、いいだろ？風の色、特徴だぜ。
Water that never runs out no matter how much you drink, pretty cool right? That's Kazama Iroha's signature.
よし、はい。というわけで、次のね、曲に行きたいと思うんですけども、
Alright, yes. So, I'd like to move on to the next song,
まああの、昨日のね、お話でちょっと匂わせをしたんですが、本日はですね、あの視聴者参加型3D生ライブとなっておりまして、
well, uh, I gave a little hint in yesterday's talk, but today is a viewer-participatory 3D live,
はい。今回はですね、皆さんに投票していただいて、次に歌う曲を決めたいと思います。
yes. This time, I'd like everyone to vote and decide the next song to sing.
なんじゃらほいって思うかもしれないんですけど、視聴者参加型曲決めガチンコってことです。
You might wonder what that is, but it's a serious audience-voted song decision battle.
それでは、テロップどうぞ！
Now then, cue the graphic!
じゃじゃーん！
Ta-da!
えー、ANIMAか、ただ声一つ。
Uh, "ANIMA" or "Tada Koe Hitotsu".
どっちか。
Which one?
で、投票が少なかった方も、この後メンバーシップ限定のアンコールライブで歌いますので、よろしくお願いします。
And whichever gets fewer votes, I'll sing it later in the membership-exclusive encore live, so please look forward to it.
いや、どちらも名曲で、まあ悩みますよね。今スタッフの一人とどっちになるかねっていうのをかけてます。
Both are masterpiece songs, so it's a tough choice. Right now, I'm making a bet with one of the staff on which one it'll be.
あのどっちにかけてるとか言わないんで、さあみんな、これで次回の差し入れが豪華になるか裏で決まるからな。はい。
I won't say which one I bet on, so everyone, whether your next catering gets luxurious or not is decided behind the scenes. Yes.
というわけで、早速投票を開始していきたいと思います。だいたい時間は1分間ぐらいですかね。
With that said, I'd like to start the voting right away. The time is about 1 minute, right?
それでは、よーい、スタート！
Well then, ready, start!
届いた？
Did it reach you?
今来たかな？
Did it arrive now?
あ、来た来た来た来た！
Ah, it's here, it's here!
はい、じゃあみんな、投票ボタン押してね！
Okay, everyone, press the voting button!
じゃあみんなが投票やってる間に、ゆっくりみんなのこと待つために、カエルわ、メインステージ。
While you're voting, I'll head back to the main stage to wait for everyone leisurely.
じゃ、移動ですよ。移動ー！
Now, time to move. Moving!
はい、というわけで、みなさん、投票した？できて る？
Alright, so everyone, did you vote? Have you done it?
どっちかだよ？
Which one is it?
ど、どっちもは、どっちもは ちょっとあれだからね、どっちか、どっちかに お願いします。
Wait, both is a bit... please choose one or the other.
そういえば今、なんだかんだこうやって歩かしてもらってますが、実はね、なにげにね、
Come to think of it, while walking around like this, actually, casually,
ファーストミッション衣装がね、見せるのが、ゆっくり見せるのは、初めてだったりするんだけど。
showing off the first mission outfit slowly for the first time,
どう？そうそう、ここで、ここで宣伝しとこう。
how is it? Oh yeah, let's make an announcement right here.
着席じゃないよ？あの、宣伝ね！
Not seating! I mean the announcement!
このあとメインでアフターライブがあるんですけど、そのね、ときに、もっと
There's an after-live on the main stage afterwards, and at that time,
このかっこいいところをね、いっぱいに見せますので、なんでぜひよかったらメインのアフターライブにも
I'll show off this cool side even more, so if you'd like, please come to the main after-live too!
お越しくださーいっていう宣伝も入れつつ、みんな入れた？入れれた？
That's my announcement while slipping it in—did everyone enter your vote? Did you get it in?
すごいなこれ花道。長くない？長、長くない？
This flower path is amazing. Isn't it long? Long, isn't it long?
これ、これ現地ライブでもやりたいなぁ。はい、もうだいぶかっこいい風真いろはをいっぱい見せているわけなんですが。
I'd love to do this at a live venue too. Yep, I've been showing off a pretty cool Kazama Iroha a lot.
いやでもどっちかな、これ。アニメはね、みんな、設定のとおりあの、かっこいい！
Well, but which one? ANIMA, as everyone set it, is cool!
かっこいい！で、ただ声一つはしっとり、しっとり。
Cool! And 'Tada Koe Hitotsu' is mellow, mellow.
なんね、これ好み分かれると思いますが。
So I think tastes will differ.
はい、や、きっとね、どっちやってもみんなかっこいいって言ってくれるよね？
Yeah, I'm sure whichever it is, everyone will say it's cool, right?
え、言ってくれるよね？え、言って、言ってくれる？お、言ってくれ…カメラは言ってくれるってことで。
Eh, you'll say it, right? Eh, you'll say it? Oh, you'll say it... camera-wise, you'll say it.
はい、というわけでみんなもうだいぶいいかな？
Right, so everyone, is it good now?
オッケー？じゃあそろそろ終わっちゃいますからね！
Okay? Then it's about to end soon!
はい、早く早く早く早く投票してね！
Quick, quick, quick, quick, vote!
え？終わった？終わったよね、スタッフさん？終わった？
Eh? Is it over? It's over, right, staff? Is it over?
早かった？歩くの。
Was it fast? Walking.
終わった？終わった、終わったかな？
Is it over? Over, is it over?
終わったらしい。
Looks like it's over.
今、掛けをステイルスタッフと睨みっこしてます。
Right now, I'm staring down the staff staging the bets.
それでは結果発表ー！
And now, announcement of the results!
たでーん！アンケートの結果、ANIMAになったみたいです！
Ta-da! Based on the survey results, it looks like ANIMA!
あ、これあの、賭けに勝った人の動きです。
Ah, this is the movement of someone who won the bet.
さすがに期待しちゃいます！よっしゃあ！
Naturally I have expectations! All right!
というわけで、あの賭けにも勝ち、皆さんも選んでいただきとてもありがたい限りですね。あの、ただ声一つのほうもこのあとメンバーシップ限定で歌いますので、そちらもお楽しみに！
So, winning the bet and having you all choose it as well, I'm very grateful. Also, 'Tada Koe Hitotsu' will be sung later exclusively for members, so please look forward to that too!
と、いうわけで、さっそく歌っていきましょうか。それでは聞いてください、「ANIMA」。
So, let's start singing right away. Now, please listen to 'ANIMA'.
魂の色は
What color is
何色ですか
the color of the soul?
もういっそ 折れたままで
Even if I just stay broken,
捨てるほど 逃げ出すほど
so much that I'd throw it away or run away,
強くはないよ ほら
I'm not strong, you see.
もう一度 鼓動高鳴る
Once again, my heartbeat echoes.
何が正しいかなんて わからないけど
I don't know what is right,
形のないものばかりが 大切になっていく
but only things without shape become precious.
飾らない言葉だけが 強く結ばれてる
Only unadorned words are bound strongly.
また躓いて 転がって それでも砕けない
Even if I stumble and roll, I still won't break.
魂の色は 何色ですか
What color is the color of the soul?
ただ傷ついて 強がって それでも見つけたいよ
Just getting hurt, acting tough, but I still want to find it.
魂のカタチ 確かめてるよ
I am verifying the shape of my soul.
深い地底の底で一人 扉と鍵を探す
Deep in the depths of the earth, alone, I search for the door and key.
おとぎ話は ほら
The fairy tale, look,
泡のように全部消えて
disappears completely like bubbles.
葛藤 残像だけ 次のページへ
Only conflict and afterimages remain, moving to the next page.
伸びてく枝葉が分かれて それぞれの道を行く
The growing branches split, each going its own path.
それぞれの道を行く
Each going our separate ways,
寂しい思い出だけが
only lonely memories
強く根を張ってる
are taking deep root.
まだ貫いて失って それでも挫けない
Still piercing through, losing things, yet refusing to break—
心はどこに 器はどこに
Where is the heart? Where is the vessel?
ただ残されて抜け落ちて それでも伝えたいよ
Left behind and slipping away, yet still I want to convey it—
魂の日々を 魂の意志を
the days of the soul, the will of the soul,
ずっと…
on and on...
魂の色は
What is the color of the soul?
何色ですか
What color is it?
赤色ですか
Is it red?
青色ですか
Is it blue?
魂の色は
What is the color of the soul?
何色ですか
What color is it?
不透明な過去に
In an opaque past,
不透明な明日に
in an opaque tomorrow,
生きるあなたは
you who live—
何色ですか
what color are you?
また躓いて転がって それでも砕けない
Stumbling and rolling over again, yet still refusing to shatter—
魂の色は 何色ですか
What is the color of the soul? What color is it?
ただ傷ついて強がって それでも見つけたいよ
Just getting hurt and acting tough, yet still I want to find it—
魂のカタチ 確かめてるよ
confirming the shape of the soul.
ずっと…
On and on...
はい、ということで、ANIMAを歌わせていただきました！
Yes, and with that, I performed "ANIMA"!
カロリー高いほうだったな、水分、摂ってください。
That was pretty high in calories... Please stay hydrated.
カロリー高いほうだった…危ない。
That was on the higher calorie side... Whew, close one.
すいません、あの、ナチュラルにマイクを返すのを忘れていました。
Sorry, um, I completely forgot to return to my natural mic.
やばい、音程になってなかったらいいな。すいません。
Oh no, I hope my pitch wasn't messed up. Sorry.
ナチュラルに、スタッフさんがすっごい手伸ばしてくれてたらね、疲れすぎてここ硬直してた。
Naturally... The staff were reaching out their hands so much, I was so exhausted my neck got all stiff.
水美味い。
Water is so good.
減らない水のおかげで生きていけてます。
Thanks to this never-ending water, I'm able to keep living.
はい、で、ちょっとこれ返して、
Right, then I'll just return this,
はい。
yep.
それではですね、ま、ちょっとまだまだ続くんですけど、風真いろはで一旦重大告知タイムをさせていただきたいと思います。
Now then, um, it's still going to continue for a bit longer, but I'd like to take a moment for Kazama Iroha's major announcement.
じゃ、まずはいつものから行くか！
Well then, first off, shall we go with the usual?
じゃ、まずはこちら！風真いろは 誕生日記念グッズ2026出まーす！どんどんどんどんどん！
First is this! Kazama Iroha's 2026 Birthday Commemorative Goods are out! Ta-da-da-da-da!
いやー、なんか良さそうなラインナップですね！今回もとーってもこだわったグッズばかりなので、楽しみにしていてほしいです！
Man, the lineup looks so good! This time too, all the goods are super carefully crafted, so I hope you're looking forward to them!
では、1つずつ商品見ていきましょう！
Now then, let's look at the items one by one!
まずは、こちら！タペストリーがでまーす！
First is this! A tapestry is out!
タペストリー、実は個人グッズで出すの超久しぶりなんですよね。イラストはもちぷよ先生描き下ろしで、雨上がりの青空の下で、本当にね、このステージみたいな感じで、あのライブをしている風真いろはのイメージで描いていただきました！ありがとうございます！
Tapestries are actually super rare for my solo goods. The illustration was newly drawn by Mochipuyo-sensei, imagining Kazama Iroha performing live under a post-rain blue sky, just like this stage! Thank you so much!
いや、めっついいよね。飾ってね。
Man, it's so good. Make sure to display it.
続いては、こちら！フード付きタオルです！
Next is this! A hooded towel!
はい、タペストリーと同じイラストのフード付きタオルです。フード部分はぽこべぇの顔になっており、取り外しが可能となっております。
It features the same illustration as the tapestry. The hood is shaped like Pokobee's face and is completely removable.
いやなんか、こないだね、あのロックスのライブあったじゃん？で、なんかダンスの先生に教えてもらったんだけど、なんか風真いろはイロにタオル購入率がよかったらしいな、お前たち首にいっぱい巻いてくれて、えらいぞ！フード付きタオル...
And you know, recently there was that Rox live, right? The dance teacher told me that the purchase rate for Kazama Iroha towels was really good—you guys wrapped them all around your necks, good job! The hooded towel...
これを進んで、あの、これでジニンポコベゴッコができるようになります。
By getting this, you'll be able to play the Shinigami Pokopeko game.
ジニンポコベゴッコをしたい方、まあ、取り外してそのまま飾りたい方にもね、どうぞ。
If you want to play the game, or display it as is, please go ahead.
はい、そしてお次はこちら！
Next up is this!
ペットボトルホルダー！
A pet bottle holder!
あの、これは風真いろはさんが欲しいの作、作、作りました。
I had this made because I really wanted one.
あの、イラストはさめあんこ先生に書いていただきました。
The illustration was drawn by Sameanko-sensei.
かわいいでしょ。この真ん中の穴に、あの、ぎゅってペットボトルのところを入れてね、
Isn't it cute? You squeeze a plastic bottle right into the hole in the middle,
あの、使うやつです。はい、めちゃおしゃれです。
and use it like that. It's super stylish,
よかったら使ってください。カバンとかね、つけて持ち歩けるんでね。
so please use it. You can attach it to your bag and carry it around.
はい！
Yes!
そしてラストはこちら！
And finally, this!
はい！実態、地味になかったセーラー服バーの風真いろはのぬいぐるみ、なんとボイス付きでーす！
Kazama Iroha's sailor uniform plushie—which surprisingly didn't exist yet—comes with voice lines!
こちらもさめあんこ先生にデザインを考えていただきました。
Sameanko-sensei also designed this one for us.
レインポンチョを着た声が出るぬいぐるみです。
It's a plushie wearing a rain poncho that makes sounds!
まあ、あの、おててを握りしめると音が出るらしいぞ。
Apparently, if you squeeze its hands, it makes a sound.
今のところはな。はい。外出時にカバンなどに付けることもできます。
Yes, you can also attach it to your bag when going out.
で、ボイスなんですけど、なんか、天気に関係するモノ撮ったんですよ。
And as for the voice lines, I recorded some related to the weather.
どんな感じかはまだね、さすがに言えないけど。
I can't really tell you what they're like just yet, of course.
だけど、あの、おみくじ感覚で聞いて、あの、その天気にならなかったからといって風真いろはを責めないでください。
Listen to them like a fortune slip, and don't blame me if the weather turns out different!
自己責任で、にぎにぎしてください。買ってからのお楽しみです。
Squeeze them at your own risk. It's a surprise after you buy them.
いっぱいありますが、グッズを見ていきましょう！
There's a lot, but let's check out the goods!
こちら！
Here!
今回のグッズはですね、聖誕のイメージに合わさて、フェス風をテーマに作ってみました。
This time, the merchandise is themed around a festival, matching the birthday image.
実用性たっぷりだし、これからの季節にぴったりなんで、よかったらよろしくお願いします。
They're super practical and perfect for the coming season, so I'd appreciate your support.
そして、フルセット購入特典は、え、こちら！
And the full set purchase bonus is, uh, this!
数量限定版あります。風真いろはの直筆サインと箔押し複製メッセージ入りチケット風カード、ちょっとおしゃれな感じですね。
A ticket-style card with Kazama's handwritten autograph and foil-stamped message—pretty stylish.
そして通常版には箔押し複製サインとメッセージ入りチケット風カードがついてきます。
The regular version comes with a ticket-style card featuring a foil-stamped autograph and message.
え、さらにどちらにも、え、まあ、ボイスがついてきますね。
Plus, both of them come with voice lines, you see.
はい。君と雨宿りというかなタイトルのボイスがついてくるんですけど、まあ、ぶっちゃけ、あの、気になったら聞いてください。
It comes with a voice track called "Taking Shelter in the Rain with You," but listen if you're curious.
ボイス、すーべめたりださーいからね。
It's all about being spoiled and pampering each other!
はい、ということで、ま、シチュエーションボイスですね。甘えどり系だった気が、なんかちぎりながら撮った気がします。
Yes, so it's a situational voice. It's a spoiled-type one recorded while feeling emotional.
そして、グッズは21時カートオープンです。
Also, the merchandise cart opens at 21:00.
すいません、あの、生配信につきちょっと時間が押しそうなんですけれど、
Sorry, since it's a live stream, things might run a little late, but
あの、ゆっくり買ってねとは言えず、頑張ってください。って言えばいいのか分からない。
I can't tell you to take your time, so please do your best.
ごめん！そして、あの21時からホロメアの、あの、多分配信控えしてると思うんですけど、あの、何も気にしなくいいんでスタートしてくださいね。
Sorry! And Holomear's stream starts at 21:00, so please don't worry and just start!
はい！そして、まだまだあります。まだまだ、それがこちら！
Yes! And there's still more. There's this!
はい！
Yes!
新曲！やったー！
A new song! Yay!
風真いろはさん、新曲が出ます！タイトルは「風向きエントロピー」。作詞作曲は「いろはステップ」でもおなじみ40mPさんに制作していただきました！
Kazama Iroha's new song "Kazamuki Entropy" produced by 40mP!
はい！配信後にこちらMVが、えっと公開されます。多分こっそり今マネちゃんがプレミア公開に切り替えてくれているはず。楽曲は0時リリースになっております！
The MV will be released after the stream. The song will be available at midnight!
はい。そして、あの、ちょっと気づいた人もいるかもしれないんですけど、ジャケットの文字は風真いろはさんが自分で書きました。はい、ありがとうございます。
Some of you might have noticed, but Kazama Iroha wrote the letters on the jacket herself.
というわけで、もう終わっちゃうんですけど、なんかすごいトレンド2とかに入ってるっていう連絡を受けました。くそっ！
With that, we're almost done, but I heard we're trending around #2. Damn it!
あと残り頑張ってくれと言いたいけど、
I want to say do your best for the rest,
でもみんな本当にいっぱいポストしてくれてありがとね。
but everyone, thank you so much for posting so much.
よし、準備できた？大人の準備ができてそうなんで、
All right, are you ready? Adult preparations seem ready,
早速新曲歌ってきたいと思います！がしかし、
so I'd like to go ahead and sing the new song!
今回はちょっと特別なもの用意してきました。
This time we've prepared something a little special.
ゴンドラ！こいっ！
Gondola! Come out!
おお、リハーサルで見たけどやっぱいいなこれ。
I saw it in rehearsal, but it really is great.
というわけでにんみんなポコベがいなくて寂しかったでしょ？今年は、ゴンドラになりました。
You missed Pokobe, right? This time, it became a gondola.
というわけで、早速やっていくんですが、
So, we'll get right into it,
ドア、オープン！
door, open!
いえーい！ほっ。乗っちゃうもんね。
Yay! I'm getting on.
というわけで、早速歌っていきたいと思います。
With that, I'd like to sing it right away.
それでは聞いてください。風真いろは新オリジナル曲「風向きエントロピー」。
Please listen. Kazama Iroha's new original song, "Kazamuki Entropy."
ねぇ、いつからそこにあったの？
Hey, since when have you been right there?
あまりにも近すぎて気づかなかったよ。
You were so close I didn't even notice.
ずっと私が生まれた日から
Ever since the day I was born,
そばにいてくれたのにね
you've been right by my side all along.
想像してたよりも、うまく笑えない
I can't smile as well as I'd imagined,
だけどそれ以上に、世界は優しくて
but even more than that, the world is gentle,
いつか風が生まれた 足跡が始まる場所
where the wind was born someday, where footsteps begin.
あの日の私に戻って出掛け出したとしても ここにくるんだろう
Even if I went back to that day and set out anew, I'd end up right here.
この景色も この声も 私を彩るすべて
This scenery, this voice, everything that colors me—
本当になんて まだわからないけど
I still don't know if it's real,
ただ風の吹くままに
but I'll just go where the wind blows.
ねぇ、いつから気づいてたの まるで私のこと全部をお見通しで
Hey, since when did you notice? As if you saw right through everything about me.
苦しい紛れにごまかした嘘も 君にばれていたのかな
Were the lies I made up in desperation exposed to you as well?
平凡で退屈で 欠伸ばかりで 変哲のないありふれてる時間
Ordinary and boring, full of yawns, uneventful and mundane days.
想像してただけじゃ 何も変わらない だけどそれ以上に
Just imagining wouldn't change anything, but even more than that—
予想してた以上に
beyond what I anticipated—
ほら 新しい風が吹いてきて 昨日よりも自分が猛烈に愛しく思えたんだ
Look, a new wind started blowing, and I found myself loving who I am even more fiercely than yesterday.
ああー
Ah...
いつか風がやんで 足跡が途切れた場所
Someday the wind will stop, at the place where footsteps fade away,
落とし物探して拾って見つけ出せたから ここにいるんだろう
searching, picking up what was lost, and finding it—that's why I'm here.
そう 髪が靡く
Yes, my hair streams in the wind.
いつか夢見た 青空と交わる場所
The place where I once dreamed of meeting the blue sky,
廻り道選んで迷って躓いたとしても そこへ行くんだろう
even if I take detours, get lost, and stumble, I'll head right there.
この景色も この声も 私を彩るすべて
This scenery, this voice, everything that colors me—
等身大の手で 握りしめて
grasping it with my own two hands,
想像以上にもっと 自由な速度で
at a speed even freer than imagined.
本当になんて まだわからないけど ただ風の吹くままに
I still don't know if it's real, but I'll just go where the wind blows.
誰かの吹くままに
Just as the wind blows.
はーいというわけで ありがとうございましたー！
Ha-ii, and with that, thank you very much!
よいしょ みんなすっかり忘れてるわけだ
Phew, everyone totally forgot, didn't they?
今日これから 記念撮影しまーす！
Today, from now on, we're going to take a commemorative photo!
そう お土産があるって言ったっしょ？
Yeah, I said there would be a souvenir, right?
これこれ！ よちょで まじで 自撮り棒 リハーサルでめっちゃ練習したのに
This, this! Yochode, seriously, I practiced a lot with the selfie stick during rehearsal,
自撮り棒下手 あ、いかじ いかじ
but I'm bad at the selfie stick. Ah, squidji, squidji...
かしゃ うし いけるぞ いけるぞ おっけー
Snap. Okay, I can do it, I can do it. Okay!
はーい というわけで みなさん 今日お土産ありって言いましたね？
So, with that everyone, I said today there would be a souvenir, right?
そうなんです！ 今日撮った、今この風がね 自撮り棒で撮った写真が
That's right! The photo we took today, this wind right here, the photo taken with the selfie stick—
コンビニで なんとプリントアウトできます！ すすごーい！
at convenience stores, you can actually print it out! Amazing!
はい！ こちらですね、対象店舗 ファミリーマートさん ローソンさん ミニストップさんで 本日21時から ネットで事前購入ができます！
Yes! Starting today at 9:00 PM, you can pre-purchase it online at participating stores: FamilyMart, Lawson, and Ministop!
お値段がですね、税込み300円とのこと 印刷できるようになるのは 明日の6月19日 20時からになっております。
The price is 300 yen including tax, and you'll be able to print it starting tomorrow, June 19th, at 8:00 PM.
写真にはですね、手書きメッセージ あのこの後書きますんで はい！ どんな写真が撮れているか
The photo will feature a handwritten message that I'll write right after this! So yeah! Check what kind of photo was taken—
ちょっと写真下手くそでも怒らないでね！ あの内容は買ってから確認してください。
don't get mad even if my photography skills are bad! Please check the contents after buying it.
いやすごいよね！ ちょっといち早く皆さんのもとに なんか手元に残るライブのお土産が用意できればということで 今回やらせていただきました！ お土産ありまーす！
Yeah, it's amazing! I wanted to prepare a live souvenir that you could have in your hands as quickly as possible, so that's why we did this this time! There's a souvenir!
ちょっと 皆さん 各自で回収 って形で
Just a heads up, everyone
それだけが 申し訳ないんですが お見送りがありますんで
will need to collect them yourselves, but there'll be a send-off.
是非 気になったら コンビニでプリントしてみてください!
If you're interested, please try printing them at a convenience store!
そして コンビニプリント購入できるのは 7月21日 17時59分までです!
Convenience store printing is available until July 21st at 5:59 PM!
概要欄に 写真こういうの リンクタブにも まれちゃんがやってくれてると思いますので よろしくお願いします!
Mare-chan has put photo links in the description and tabs, so check them out!
そして この後はですね MVの公開と メンバーシップ限定の アンコールライブ ありますので そちらも絶対 聞いてください!
After this, we have the MV premiere and membership-exclusive encore live, so don't miss them!
それでは皆さん またお会いしましょう!
Well then everyone, let's meet again!
最高の お誕生日でした! バイバーイ!
It was the absolute best birthday! Bye-bye!
ねえ いつからそこにあったの？
Hey, when was it there?
あまりにも近すぎて気づかなかったよ
It was so close I didn't even notice.
ずっと私が生まれた日からそばにいてくれたのにね
Even though you'd been by my side since the day I was born.
曖昧で複雑で予測不可能な
Vague, complex, and unpredictable,
気まぐれに変わってゆく空の模様
the ever-changing patterns of the sky.
想像していたようにうまく笑えない
I can't smile as well as I imagined.
だけどそれ以上に世界は優しくて
But even more than that, the world is gentle.